Guide to the Audio Tapes Related to Robert Creeley and His Personal and Artistic Circles MSS.MEDIA.0001
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Audio tapes related to Robert Creeley and his personal and artistic circles
1959-1969
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Creeley, Robert, 1926-2005
MSS.MEDIA.0001
2 Linear Feet
Collection consists of 71 reel to reel audio tapes documenting poetry readings and lectures of many of the better known 20th century poets.
Scope and Content of Collection
Collection consists of 71 reel to reel audio tapes documenting poetry readings and lectures of many of the better known 20th century poets.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 2002
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Creeley, Robert, 1926-2005
- Creeley Stories; Walter Chappell and Taos men: piano + drums (Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Side one: Creeley reading three stories (Mr Bwe; Jardov; The Boat) recorded by CBC at the UBC Arts Festival. Vancouver - reading in Public LIbrary downtown - February 1962. Side Two: Walter Chappel: piano; Mend from the Taos pueblo; drums. Recorded 1965
- Allen Ginsberg; Pakistani Brothers, Moldy tape. (Folder 2)
  Allen Ginsberg: Reading at St. John's, Santa Fe (Feb 2 1966). Pakistani Brothers: Nayumat ali Khan & Salimit Ali Kahn "Classical Music from Pakistan" - HMV Clip 1308. 1) Rag Kalavati. 2)Later Portions o Rag Durbari
- A Sense of Measure - Robert Creeley; Poetry Reading - Robert Creeley, two track recording 3 3/4 ips. Track 1 85'35", Track 2 78'20". Moldy Tape. (Folder 3)
  University of California, Berkeley Language Laboratory #556
- Kramer concluded; Centurypeoms Voices; Cage (2); John Wieners; Spock - Coffin (Folder 4)
  Reel Housing contains detailed contents listing.
- Bromige; Duerden; Loewinsohn (Folder 5)
- Robert Creely: Amarillo (Folder 6)
  Reel housing indicates tape once contained Mozart concertos.
- Creeley: SF State Campus and U of C Readings (Folder 7)
  1. Not Recorded 2. Roetry Center, SF State Campus 10/17/1962 - 1:00 PM Note: the above was 2nd in series of three
- Sympathy Robert Creeley, Moldy Tape (Folder 8)
  Title information obtained from artwork on reel to reel box
- Creeley Tape, Moldy Tape (Folder 9)
  Play list included with reel
- Creeley (2): Hartcrane Net Program (1), 1966; Moldy Tape (Folder 10)
  Play list included with Reel
- Creeley (Tufts); Little; Rose, Moldy Tape (Folder 11)
  Side 1: Robert Creeley - Reading - Tufts, March 5 1969 Side 2: Robert Creeley - cont; Bill Little, Tufts Mar 6 1969; Bobe Rose, Tufts, Mar 6 1969.
- Kozikowski / Fielding Dawson Reading: NYC - June 14, 1961, 1961 June 14 (Folder 12)
- Witter Bynner / Musique Concrete (Folder 13)
- Kessler (Folder 14)
- Walter Chapell + Indian Drummer et al. (Folder 15)
- Creeley - Merwin - Snyder, Single Track. (Folder 16)
- Robert Creeley 1967 (Folder 17)
  Robert Creeley's poetry reading, Dec 14, 1967 Rosary Hill College. Recorded at request of Jacquelyn Moulin Cultural Committee Rocorded in Wick Lounge at 8:00PM. Tape Speed 3 3/4 by BP of AVC-RHC
- Duncan Lecture; Wieners Lectures (Folder 18)
- The Sullen Art: Robert Creeley, Dave Ossman (Folder 19)
- Fielding Dawson Interview, Moldy Tape (Folder 20)
- Oppen, Weaver, Jandl: McBeth in Concrete Poetry (Folder 21)
- ? [unknown], Moldy tape (Folder 22)
- Witter Bynnerg (Folder 23)
- George Oppen - Ed Dorn 1967 (Folder 24)
  1. George Oppen, 2/17/67. State University of New York at Buffalo, from soon to be published book. 2. Ed Dorn, 6/22/67. from The North Atlantic Turbine peoms State University of New York at Buffalo.
- Creeley (Folder 25)
- William Moore / Allen Ginsberg / Ed Dorn (Folder 26)
- Duncan, Spicer, Blaser: Berkeley (Folder 27)
- Robert Creeley Final Cut Poetry Tape (Folder 28)
- Olson: Cortland, N.Y. Fall '67 (Folder 29)
  Charles Olson, Poetry on the Campus. 10/20/67.
- Zukofsky / Blaser (Folder 30)
- Dorn 1967 (Folder 31)
  Edward Dorn; Buffalo - June 22, 1967.
- Bob's Feb 16 UBC Reading (Folder 32)
  Reel Housing Contains detailed listing of contents.
- Vancouver 63 - Olson, Creeley, Duncan, Ginsberg (Folder 33)
- Tom Pickard, Moldy Tape (Folder 34)
  Tom Pickard (At lexden Rd, Colchester, May 66.)
- Duncan Vancouver Reading,; Creeley/Ginsberg Morning (Folder 35)
- Ferlinghetti / Whalen / Zukofsky ? (Folder 36)
  (NET - USA Poetry 1966 - poor quality )
- Duncan / Kerouac (Folder 37)
- Toronto. Raymond Souster - Oct 21. 1961 (Folder 38)
  1. Raymond Souster interview and reading. 2. Edward Dorn reading and talking.
- Creeley interviewing Max Finstein; Robert Duncon (Folder 39)
- Phil Whalen (Folder 40)
- Wieners / Williams (Folder 41)
- Finlay, Corman, Duncan (Folder 42)
  Finlay Short Story; Finlay Rading his own poems; Cid Corman readings Zukosky; Cid Corman reading his own poems Duncan, Spring 1964 - UNM also rerecording of two presenations from Vancouver reading
- Ginsberg - Vancouver - Mike McClure, Moldy Tape (Folder 43)
  Side One: Ginsberg Reading Early Poems, Vancouver July 31/63, 0-950 950-1015 McClure at the Lion House Side Two: Ginsberg Reading from Journals, Vancouver Aug 2/63, 0-1035
- The Berkeley Poetry Conference; track one Olson (reading) continued; track two Olson (reading) continued, two track recording (Folder 44)
- Duncan Lectures; Robert Duncan Buffalo 67, 1967; Moldy Tape (Folder 45)
  Side One: Duncan Letr. Buffalo, April 30/67. Side Two: Duncan Letr. Buffalo, May 4/67
- The Berkeley Poetry Conference - Charles Olson: lecture, reading. (Folder 46)
- Dorn Interview / Duncan #3 / Pound, Moldy Tape (Folder 47)
- SomebodytalkingaboutBeats (Folder 48)
- Creeley: Stories (Folder 49)
  Creeley - Reading from The Gold Diggers
- Creeley / Crane (2) (Folder 50)
  Creeley Lecture Canisino College - Buffalo 12/1/66 Hart Crane: NGT program - 2 (continued) - starts 248
- Reichert - Trocchi - Dorn - Vanderbeek - Cage Bunting (Folder 51)
  Reel Housing contains contents listing.
- John Chamberlain / Mina Loy (Folder 52)
  Mina Loy - talking and reading Aspen. August 15, 1965 (Robert Van Dias and Paul Blackburn) John Chamberlain (talking with R. & B. [?] Pac[?]tas, spring 1965)
- Bunting concluded; Zukofsky; Olson; Troochi. etc. (Folder 53)
- Olson et al conversation concluded; Cyrus Gordon; Samuel Noah Kramer (Folder 54)
- Olson; Maximus II; and earlier poems, Vancouver 64' (Folder 55)
  Charles Olson. Vancouver. Aug 16, 1963: Second half of new Maximus book followed by earlier materials. USA Poetry - spring 1966 (Gloucester) - begins 742 (NET)
- Olson; Maximus II; Levertov (Folder 56)
  Part 1 of 2. Part two continued on reel 55. Reel Housing Contains contents listing.
- Ornetti Coleman / Winfield Scott / Charlie Parker (Folder 57)
- Zukofsky, Pound, Creeley (Folder 58)
  Green a) Louis Zukofsky, Fuffalo Festival of the Arts, Albright -Knox, 4 March 1968, introduction by R. Creeley. b) Ezra Pound, Reading after Spoleto Festival, 16-17 July 1966 Red a) Robert Creeley, Reading to Musical Settings by Michael Harwood Baird Hall, Sunyab, 16 April 1968
- Buckminster Fuller Talk (Folder 59)
- Buckminster Fuller Talk (Folder 60)
- Buckminster Fuller Talk, 1968 Mar 11; Moldy Tape. (Folder 61)
- Schwitters; H.D.; Joyce//Dorn (Vancouver, Feb. 63), 1963 Feb (Folder 62)
- Robert Creeley: Reading from Pieces, U.N.M. Oct. 11th, 1968, 1968 Oct 11 (Folder 63)
- Gael Turnbull, Moldy Tape (Folder 64)
- Allen Ginsberg (Folder 65)
- Abby Hoffman - Dave Stein (Folder 66)
  Reel Housing contains detailed description of contents.
- Sound Poetry - Joanne; Ed Sanders; Mclaire; Harwood (Folder 67)
  Reel Housing has detailed description of contents.
- Gary Snyder - Treson, Fall 1964 (Folder 68)
- Blackburn (Folder 69)
- Robert Creeley, U of Chicago Reading 1-20-68 (Folder 70)
  Reel Housing contains detailed listing of contents.
- Ricard Alpert: Sunyab - March 15, 67', 1967 Mar 15; Moldy Tape (Folder 71)